American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Edward] Hallowell, April 18, 1856; 4 3/4" x 7 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    "On a new genus of Boaedae from Cuba," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Robert Bridges, Isaac Hays, Joseph Leidy. Publication in, Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the president of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 19, 1856; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.A. Thomas. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, April 23, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Ethnological Society of London
    A.L.S.: Richard Cull. 3p.,end.by C.B. T[rego], Forwards publication through Henry Stevens
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, May 1, 1856; 5 1/8" x 8"; Snell, E. S. (Ebenezer Strong), 1801-1876
    Amherst College, 1 p. A.L.S. Regarding back numbers of A.P.S. Proceedings due to the library of Amherst College.
  - Letter to Stephen Alexander, May 13, 1856; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. Dr.L. Unsigned. Regarding settlement of accounts of the Astronomische Nachrichten. See Alexander to Trego, June 4, 1856.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, May 14, 1856; 5" x 8"; Piggot, A. Snowden (Aaron Snowden), 1822-1869
    Baltimore, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses paper on Colombian guano.
  - Letter to Charles D. [sic] Trego, May 21, 1856; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, [Washington], 2 pp. A.L.S. Requests numbers 45 and 46 of A.P.S. Proceedings. FILM235 FRAME 23
  - Letter to F. A.[sic] Trego, May 22, 1856; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Kirkpatrick, James A.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests return of copy of Proceedings of American Association for the Advancement of Science that he left at A. P. S. rooms.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, May 28, 1856; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Chauvenet, William
    Librarian of A.P.S., Annapolis, 1 p. A.L.S. The librarian of the U. S. Naval Academy inquires as to the availability of a complete set of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, May 30, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Tingley, W. H.
    Secretary of A.P.S., St. Louis, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Announcement of the organization of the Academy of Science of St. Louis. See Pro., VI, 198.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, June 4, 1856; 5" x 7 7/8"; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Princeton, 2pp. A.L.S. Encloses draft in payment of account for Astronomische Nachrichten. See Trego to Alexander, May 13, 1856.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 12, 1856; Lambdin, J.B.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, June 30, 1856; New Jersey Historical Society
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical society], July 9, 1856; 7 x4-1/2; Baikie, William Balfour, 1825-1864
    Portsmouth, A.L.S. 1P., end. by E.O.K[endall]. Donates publication.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, July 10, 1856; 7 3/8" x 9 15/16"; Chauvenet, William
    Librarian of A.P.S., Annapolis, 1 p. A.L.S. Orders a complete set of A.P.S. Transactions for the library of the U.S. Naval Academy.
  - Report of the committee... upon a paper by Edw[ar]d Hallowell, July 18, 1856; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Scincidae in the collection of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia," [Philadelphia] 1 p. D.S.: John L. LeConte, Robert Bridges, Isaac Lea. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred the paper by Dr. [Joseph] Leidy, July 18, 1856; 4 1/2" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    "On the remains of the walrus discovered on the coast of the United States," [Philadelphia],1 p. D.S.: Sdw[ard] Hallowell, John F. Frazer, John [L.] Leconte. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 31, 1856; 10x8; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thos. G. Cary, Pres.and W.F. Poole, Libn. 1p., end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 1, 1856; 10x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James Walker, pres.and John Langdon Sibley, Libn. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 1, 1856; 9x7; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, A.L.S.: Samuel H. Congar. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall].and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Aug. 2, 1856; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Hosmer. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., Charleston, August 2, 1856; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; Gibbs, Lewis R.
    1 p. A.L.S. The Charleston Library Society orders A.P.S. Transactions, X, "and any succeeding volumes."
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, August 8, 1856; 7 3/4" x 10"; Stone, Edwin M.
    Secretary of A.P.S., Providence, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Librarian of the Rhode Island Historical Society requests the cooperation of Mr. Trego in his biographies of John Howland and Mannaseh Cutler.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, Philadelphia, Sept. 7, 1856; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, A.L.S.: W.Vrolik. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] In French. Asks for APS publications which are wanting in their library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 15, 1856; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Saunders, Henry D.
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p.and end. Wishes to copy bust of Jefferson.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, September 24, 1856; 4 7/8" x 7 5/8"; Gibbs, Lewis R.
    Secretary of A.P.S., Charleston, 2 pp. A.P.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Transactions, X. Wishes Charleston Library Society to be entered as a subscriber.
  - Subscriptions for the benefit of John Lewis, September 29, 1856; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; American Philosophical Society
    janitor, of the American Philosophical Society, who broke his leg... [Philadelphia], ----, 1855. 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Balance due paid Mrs. Lewis, September 29, 1856. Document of value for autographs. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to C[harles B.] Trego, September 29, 1856; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Chauvenet, William
    Annapolis, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that complete set of A. P. S. Transactions be sent to the library of the U. S. Naval Academy.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, Oct. 6, 1856; 8x5; Cresson, John C. (John Chapman), 1806-1876
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Borrows the bust of Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 218
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia], October 7, 1856; 4 7/8" x 8 1/8"; Saunders, Henry D.
    1 p. A.D.S. Receipt given by Mr. Saunders upon the loan of a portrait and bust of Thomas Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 422
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, October 17, 1856; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Trubner, Nicolas, 1817-1884
    London, 2 pp. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of January 25. Concerning work on his new edition of Bibliographical Guide to American Literature.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 24, 1856; 10x8; Sully, Thomas, 1783-1872
    Philadelphia, L.in 3d P. 1p.,end.by J.L.Lec[onte]. Wishes to borrow portrait of Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 219
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, October 28, 1856; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; Doran, Edward C.
    Annapolis, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will settle account of $78.33, due by U. S. Naval Academy to the A.P.S., upon return of the proper receipt by the latter.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 4, 1856; 14-3/4x9-1/4; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Robert Wm. Mylne. 1p.,end.: J.P.L[esley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred two papers by Joseph Leidy, December 5, 1856; 5 1/4" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: John L. LeConte, Isaac Lea, John F. Frazer. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Jan. 18, 1857; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p..end.by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, February 2, 1857; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Adamson, John Constantine
    New York, 2PP. A.L.S. "I have taken it into my head to rattle off... a sort of Article for your Society."
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, February 7, 1857; 5" x 8"; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Princeton, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses check and stamps in payment of bill.
  - Letter to [Charles B. Trego], February 16, 1857; 7 5/8" x 9"; Bossange, Paul
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1p. A.L.S. Has forwarded a package of books received from Paris.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred a paper by Dr. [J. C.] Adamson, March 6, 1857; 8 1/2" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    "Notes on certain modes of measuring minute intervals of time," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: John F. Frazer, E. Otis Kendall, Geo[rge] M. Justice. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to [John K. Kane], March 25, 1857; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Boardman, Henry A. (Henry Augustus), 1808-1880
    President of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Declines to prepare obituary notice of Dr. [Elisha K.] Kane. See Pro., VI, 247.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, April 14, 1857; 5 1/8" x 8 1/16"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Secretary of A.P.S., Savannah, 1 p. A.L.S. Will try to prepare an obituary notice of Dr. [Elisha Kent] Kane.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, May 29, 1857; 8x5; Grigsby, Hugh Blair, 1806-1881
    Norfolk, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. Donates publications.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, June 11, 1857; 7 3/8" x 10"; Wagner, Tobias
    Geneva, 3pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding astronomical work at Rome during the winter of 1856-1857. See Pro., VI, 261.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, June 17, 1857; 8 1/8" x 10 1/8"; Smyth, C. B., jr.
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses form to be filled out in order that a box of books for the A.P.S. may be released from the custom house.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, June 23, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Getz, Charles S.
    Baltimore Museum, [Baltimore], 1 p. A.L.S. Offers a Rembrandt Peale portrait of Dr. Patterson to the A.P.S. for $25.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, July 23, 1857; 4 15/16" x 7 15/16"; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, 1 p. L.S. Has index to Astronomische Nachrichten, XXI-XL. Can furnish the same to A.P.S. at once.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, July 29, 1857; 5" x 8"; Smyth, C. B., jr.
    New York, 1 p. A.L.S. Has forwarded parcel of books from the custom house to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, August 8, 1857; 4 15/16" x 7 15/16"; Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891
    Madison, Wis., 1 p. A.L.S. The secretary of the Wisconsin Historical Society has forwarded a box of books and pamphlets to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 22, 1857; 8x5; Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, September 16, 1857; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Sheldon, D. S.
    Davenport, Iowa, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to obtain such volumes of the A.P.S. Transactions as contain Isaac Lea's articles on shells.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, September 19, 1857; 5" x 8 1/8"; Irving and Willey
    New York, 1 p. L.S. A package of books for the A.P.S. has arrived at the New York custom house. Wants to know if the same should be forwarded.
  - Letter to Francesco Cav. Zantedeschi, Sept. 25, 1857; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S.: Chal.B.Trego. 1p. Copy. Praises his work on electricity and comments on it. Presented by Antonio Pace, June 1962.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., September 29, 1857; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Foster, William C., Jr.
    to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Bloomfield, Indiana, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to subscribe to A.P.S. Transactions, and to know whether he may be come a member of the Society.
  - Letter to the American Philos[ophical] Society, October 20, 1857; 7 3/4'' x 9 3/4''; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Presents a copy of Hansen's Tables of the Moon to the A.P.S. FILM 235 FRAME 24
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, October 27, 1857; 7 3/4" x 10"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Secretary of A.P.S., Bangor, Me., 1 p. A.L.S. Notice of his election to membership in the A.P.S. has been delivered to Capt. [Andrew A.] Humphreys.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 5, 1857; 14-3/4x9-1/4; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Warington Smyth. 1p.,end.: J.P.L[esley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 20, 1857; 4 7/8" x 8"; Ellet, Charles, 1810-1862
    Jr., to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests a copy of the last Annual Report of the secretary of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Charles B. Trego?], December 12, 1857; 4 3/8" x 7"; Gregory, John
    New York, 4 pp. A.L.S. Offers rare books, magazines, coins, etc. for sale.
  - Letter to ----, December 26, 1857; 5" x 8"; Loomis, Elias, 1811-1889
    New York University, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to obtain A.P.S. Proceedings, nos. 55 and 56.
  - Compensation of C.B. Trego, Librarian, 1848-1857, American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., January 9, 1858; 4 15/16" x 8"; Gay, A. M.
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests a short account of the A.P.S. for the American Educational Year Book for 1858.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 26, 1858; 5 1/4" x 8"; Swallow, G. C. (George Clinton), 1817-1899
    Secretary of A.P.S., Columbia, Mo., 1 p. A.L.S. The state geologist of Missouri desires a complete set of the A. P. S. Transactions.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1858; 10x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. Donates reports.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, February 1, 1858; 4 3/4" x 7 9/16"; Rhees, William Jones, 1830-1907
    Smithsonian Institution, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Desires information respecting the library of the A.P.S. for report on public libraries in the United States.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February 13, 1858; 5 1/4" x 8"; Balliere, H. E.
    New York, 1 p. A.L.S. Inquires as to availability of complete sets and odd volumes of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, February 22, 1858; 4 3/8" x 7"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    Secretary of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. A.L.S. Regarding the death of Judge [John K.] Kane. See Pro., VI, 289-290.
  - Report of committee on revising the laws., Feb., 1858; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [after] D.S.: John L. LeConte, M. Robinson, W. Parker Foulke, Edward King, Franklin Bache, John Bell, F. Fraley, 1p.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, March 1, 1858; 6 3/8" x 8 1/16"; Jarvis, Edward, 1803-1884
    Librarian of A.P.S., Dorchester, Mass., 1 p. A.L.S. Is forwarding a package of reports to the A.P.S. library, through Little and Brown, of Boston.
  - Letter to [Charles B. Trego, March 2, 1858; 4 1/2" x 7 3/16"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that Dr. [John L.] LeConte be informed of his appointment to committee on Mr. [Moncure] Robinson's resolution.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, March 8, 1858; 4 15/16" x 7 15/16"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that each person on subjoined list be informed of his appointment on Mr. [Moncure] Robinson's committee.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, March 10, 1858; 10x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Chicago, A.L.S. 3p.,end.by LeC[onte]. Presents charts to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., March 10, 1858; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Begs to be excused from serving on committee on Mr. [Moncure] Robinson's resolution.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, March 11, 1858; 4 3/8" x 7"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that Dr. [Isaac] Hays be informed of his appointment to committee on Mr. [Moncure] Robinson's resolution.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, April 20, 1858; 4 1/4" x 7 5/8"; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. 3d. per. N.S. Request that T[homas] P. James be allowed to borrow [Henry] Muhlenberg's collection of mosses.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., May 7, 1858; 8" x 9 1/2"; Hayes, I. I. (Isaac Israel), 1832-1881
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Intends to make an effort to reach the North Pole. Plans approved by the American Association for the Advancement of Science. See Pro., VI, 309.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, June 2, 1858; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Whitehead, William A. (William Adee), 1810-1884
    Librarian of A.P.S., Newark, N. J., 1 p. A.L.S. The secretary of the New Jersey Historical Society forwards vol. V of its Collections to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] Fraley, June 8, 1858; 5" x 8"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Declines nomination for presidency of the A.P.S. See Pro., VI, 318.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Librarian of A.P.S., July 5, 1858; 8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Is forwarding some publications of Professor [Francisco] Zantedeschi to the A.P.S. Attended meeting of the Academy of Sciences with Charles Lucien Bonaparte.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, July 14, 1858; 5 1/2" x 8 7/8"; Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891
    Madison, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt or A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., I-X. Inquires as to availability of old series.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, August 2, 1858; 5" x 8"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Secretary of A.P.S., Chicago, 1 p. A.L.S. Gives Chicago address to which his extra numbers of the Bulletin are to be sent.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Aug. 19, 1858; 10x8; Loosey, Charles F.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,end. by LeC[onte]. Forwards publication from the K.K.geographische gesellschaft in Wien and suggests exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, September 16, 1858; 5" x 7 7/8"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Dudley Observatory, Albany, 1p. A.L.S. Will transmit subscription to Astronomische Nachrichten to Professor Peters.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, September 18, 1858; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; J. B. Lippincott Company
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p. L.S. Has been instructed by the Commissioner of Indian Affairs to deliver the sixth volume of [Henry Rowe] Schoolcraft's Indian History to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, September 30, 1858; 5" x 7 7/8"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Dudley Observatory, [Albany], 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of subscription to Astronomische Nachrichten.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, Dec. 25, 1858; 6-1/2x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. Gives money to aid APS publications.
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, December 31, 1858; 4 7/8" x 7 3/8"; Frazer, John Fries, 1812-1872
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Resigns from membership in the A.P.S. See Pro., VII, 2.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Chase's paper on Sanscrit anaglogies, 1858; 6x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [ca. ?] D.S.: J. P. Lesley, Edward King and S.S. Haldeman. 1p.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, January 16, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Chicago, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that a set of Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences be forwarded in the same package with material from the A.P.S.
  - Letter to E. O[tis] Kendall, January 17, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Chicago, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses list of mistakes found in the proofs of his work, which he requests Mr. Kendall to have corrected.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, January 31, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Chicago, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses donation of $33.62, in aid of publication of 60th. number of A.P.S. Proceedings. See Pro., VII, 6.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, February 26, 1859; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Horsfield, Joseph; Horsfield, Sarah
    Bethlehem, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. The heirs of Joseph Horsfield reclaim a volume of manuscripts from the A.P.S. Enclosed in: Jordan and Brother to Trego, Feb. 28, 1859. See Pro., VII, 9.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, February 28, 1859; 7 3/8" x 9"; Jordan and Brother
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Encloses order from the heirs of Joseph Horsfield for a volume of manuscripts. See Pro., VII, 9.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 12, 1859; 10x7-3/4; New York Academy of Sciences
    Printed L.filled in in m.sS.: John H. Redfield. 1p.end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of the committee upon papers submitted by [F. V.] Hayden and [Joseph] Leidy, March 18, 1859; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: John L. LeConte, J.[Peter] Lesley, Caspar Wister. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 26, 1859; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Association for the Advancement of Science
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Lovering. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] and add. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, March 31, 1859; 10x7-1/2; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Hosmer. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 1, 1859; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Harvard University
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, April 5, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Secretary of A.P.S., Chicago, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Trego to have corrected a typographical error in A.P.S. Proceedings, no. 60.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 6, 1859; 9-3/4x8; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thos. G. Cary, Pre.and W.F.Poole, Libn, 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred a paper by E[lias] Durand, April 15, 1859; 7 7/8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "A sketch of the botany of the basin of the Great Salt Lake of Utah," [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: Robert Bridges, Geo[rge] B. Moore, Jos[eph] Carson. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to Eli K. Price, April 27, 1859; 5" x 8"; O'Brien, John
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses bill for taxes on property of the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1859; 9-3/4x8; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Blacklock and Edward Charlton. 1p.,end.:J.P.L[esley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 19, 1859; 14-1/2x9-1/4; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S: Thomas H. Huxley. 1p.,end.: J.P.L[esley]. Thanks for Proceedings.